Contato

raquelcgaspar@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/raquelgaspar (LinkedIn)

Principais competências

Social Media Marketing Customer Service English

Languages

Chinese-Mandarin (Elementary)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Professional Working)

Certifications

Introduction to Data Studio
Search Marketing Strategies: SEO &
SEA Foundations
Digital Marketing Foundations
Google Ads Search Certification
Email Marketing Certified

Raquel Gaspar

Marketing Digital | E-Commerce | E-Mail Marketing Lisbon Area, Portugal

Resumo

I'm a Digital Marketing professional, specializing in E-mail campaigns, Affiliate Marketing and E-commerce businesses.

For 3 years I have worked in e-commerce companies and Digital Marketing Agencies, and have also acquired experience in headhunting qualified human resources for Marketing positions.

I am a fan of travel, technology, design, psychology and social entrepreneurship.

Experiência

Digital Marketing
Digital Marketing Specialist
janeiro de 2020 - Present (4 meses)

Sabbatical Period agosto de 2019 - dezembro de 2019 (5 meses)

MOBIPIUM

Business Manager | E-mail Marketing Specialist novembro de 2018 - julho de 2019 (9 meses) Lisboa e Região, Portugal

- Prospecting and handling deal negotiations with Clients and Affiliate partners from 17 different countries.
- Regularly monitoring, analyzing and reporting CPA, CPL, CPC and CPM email marketing campaigns.
- Maintaining liaison with IT and Accounting teams to ensure partners' needs were being met.
- Managing internal email databases and creating marketing campaigns to run on them.

- Building briefings and handling ongoing development of templates with the Design team for email marketing campaigns.
- Planning and managing the implementation of a new website and an Affiliates' platform to translate the company's new image.
- Requesting and monitoring the implementation of new functionalities in the company's internal software, with the purpose of optimizing the team's work and facilitate the reporting of results.

360Imprimir

CRM & Affiliate Marketing Analyst - E-Commerce junho de 2017 - outubro de 2018 (1 ano 5 meses)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

- Managing email, display, push notifications and SMS marketing campaigns in the Portuguese, Spanish, Brazilian and Mexican markets.
- Monitoring, analyzing and reporting campaigns' performance.
- Defining products and discounts for each campaign.
- Managing Affiliates (direct and affiliate networks) and negotiating new partnerships.
- Searching for and recruiting new Affiliates.
- Coming up with creative concepts for the campaigns and building briefings for the Design Team.
- Copywriting for performance-focused campaigns.

Content Ignition

Digital Affiliate Marketing Manager - International Markets novembro de 2016 - maio de 2017 (7 meses)

Lisboa e Região, Portugal

- Managing Affiliate accounts, ensuring campaigns were kept within budget and volume objectives were achieved in terms of online lead generation in the European, United States and LATAM markets.
- Identifying and recruiting new affiliate partners.
- Handling deal negotiations.
- Regularly monitoring, analyzing and reporting affiliate results and activity.
- Maintaining liaison with operations, accounting and sales to ensure both the company and affiliates' needs were managed effectively.
- Handling ongoing development and deployment of fresh marketing materials with the design team.

Michael Page

Recruitment Consulting Trainee - Commercial & Marketing julho de 2016 - outubro de 2016 (4 meses)

Page 2 of 4

Lisboa e Região, Portugal

Recruitment of middle and top-level managers for Marketing and Commercial positions.

- Database management.
- Searching for new business opportunities and potential clients.
- Sourcing and Headhunting.
- Conducting pre-screening phone interviews.
- Scheduling interviews with candidates.
- Collecting candidates' references and updating information on the progress of candidates and projects.
- Writing job descriptions, interview reports and client proposals.
- Administrative support.

Placement in Portugal
Business Development & Operations Manager
outubro de 2013 - janeiro de 2015 (1 ano 4 meses)
Lisboa e Região, Portugal

Placement in Portugal is a Portuguese startup company founded in 2012. Its mission is to help international students, graduates and young professionals find internships in Portugal that match their skills, education and preferences.

I was responsible for the overall operations of the company and collaborated directly with the founders in the development of the business strategy:

- Negotiation and establishment of 40 new agreements with client companies in 16 months (which included 75 job/internship openings in total) through email, phone and personal selling.
- Implementation of the business strategy by creating an integrated and structured process for the operations of the company.
- Creation of content for marketing materials, such as the company's website, Facebook page, flyers, business cards and brochures.
- Establishing new partnerships and fostering existing ones with higher education institutions in Portugal and abroad.
- Training and managing a team of 3 international interns.
- Analyzing CVs, conducting interviews and selecting candidates for the different available positions.

H3 Summer Intern julho de 2012 - agosto de 2012 (2 meses)

Lisboa e Região, Portugal

- Development of a database with Suggestions and Complaints from Clients, allowing the Marketing department to keep track of opinions of customers and improve customer service.
- Acquiring overall knowledge of the diverse aspects of the business by undertaking rotational responsibilities in different departments.
- Acquiring knowledge of client interaction, teamwork and team coordination by spending one week working in different stores.
- Administrative support to the financial department in order to ensure effective and efficient office operations.
- Preparing and organizing documents for the Human Resources Department.

OLÁ BACKPACKERS Hostel

Assistant Manager during Summer 2009 - 2011 (2 anos)

Lisboa e Região, Portugal

- Handling check-ins and check-outs.
- Managing online and offline reservations.
- Assisting guests and informing them about touristic attractions and other relevant information.
- Making sure the hostel was cleaned and organized at all times.

Formação acadêmica

Católica Lisbon School of Business and Economics International Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Management, Marketing Major · (2014 - 2016)

Peking University HSBC Business School Exchange student, Business Administration and Management, General · (2015 - 2016)

The University of Birmingham

Erasmus Exchange, Business Management and Marketing · (2012 - 2012)

ISEG - Lisboa School of Economics & Management Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Management · (2010 - 2014)